[The Heir]
[Episode 2]
We saved for a lifetime.
And in an instant...
it's all gone.
Mother, don't be afraid.
I'll go find work in a few days.
I won't let you and Zhen suffer.
Zhengliang, you've grown up.
Mother, where will we go?
Let's find a place nearby
to settle down first.
With your father's health...
Father.
Mother.
Your things.
Thank you, Zhen.
Not only did you of the Eighth Branch
take a life from the Li family,
but you also want to take treasures too?
This is the bone-paring knife
from my dowry.
It's my own possession.
But since it was a dowry,
it belongs to the Li family.
It's just a worldly possession.
I can do without it!
Let's go.
Father.
Sister-in-law,
Jingfu,
please wait!
Mother sent me here
to bring you some things.
These are for the children.
This is...
These are the birthday inksticks
I made for Zhen and Zhengliang.
The birthday inksticks
for the kids of the Li family
are all kept with Aunt Junru.
It's kind of Seventh Aunt to remember.
Thank you for your trouble.
Jingfu.
This is the portrait of our ancestor,
Li Tinggui.
Take it with you.
Although you have left the Li family,
Mother hopes you will not forget
that your roots will always be here.
Sister-in-law,
this is for you.
I...
Thank you, Sister-in-law.
Mother also asked me to pass on a message.
As long as there is food, there is a way.
Keep your spirits up.
Don't lose hope.
Come quickly!
Stop it!
What is this nonsense?
Benchang is leading Ronghua
to steal things!
What is going on here?
Mother,
[The eldest son of the Tian family,
Tian Benchang]
something happened to Zhen's family.
The whole family was kicked out.
I thought,
since our family has always been close
to the Eighth Branch,
[The head of the Tian family,
Tian Huai'an]
we should help them.
Mother, don't misunderstand.
Ronghua and I
saved these things ourselves.
We didn't take them from the family.
You can't use your own savings either.
Things are different now.
The Eighth Branch
has been removed from the family register
[Daughter of the Tian family,
Tian Ronghua]
and disowned.
They will be nothing
but destitute in the future.
[Mistress of the Tian family,
Wang Xiu]
I won't allow you to help them.
Zhen grew up playing with Hua and me.
She never looked down on us.
Do you dare talk back to me?
That's enough.
I think
Chang made a good point.
You are kind and righteous.
I am very pleased.
Ronghua, girls should stay at home.
Chang, go deliver your gift quickly.
Be quick.
Okay.
Stop.
Why are you running?
At a time like this,
you still want to go out?
Father.
I want to visit a friend.
You can't go.
Father,
I beg you.
Keep an eye on him.
Once the sedan and horses are ready,
you'll leave immediately.
Father!
Where are you running to?
Brother!
Brother, put me down.
I have something to tell you.
Really?
You have a lot going on for your age.
Speak.
I...
About that girl?
How about this?
If I find out anything about her,
I'll send letters to the Capital.
Is that okay?
Really?
Why would I lie to you about this?
Anything else?
Brother,
actually, I don't want to
go to the Capital at all.
I don't want to study,
and I certainly don't want to
be an official.
There's nothing there.
No one to talk to,
no one to play with.
Everything I do is wrong.
Father and my teacher
never smile at me.
If one day Father laughed with you,
wouldn't you be scared?
Brother,
I know Father means well,
but if I don't want to do something,
I just don't want to do it.
Then what do you want to do?
I...
I haven't decided yet.
But Li Zhen said I could be
a traveling merchant.
What others say doesn't count.
If a person
wants to do something,
you have to ask yourself
if you really want to do it.
Let me tell you,
first of all,
I
absolutely support you
in doing what you want.
But
you must first know what you want to do.
How can you know what you want to do?
You need to broaden your horizons.
Huizhou is small.
The Capital is big.
It has so many people.
You need to know what those people
do every day,
eat every day,
and think about every day.
When you understand it all,
you'll suddenly realize one day,
"This is what I want to do!"
Do you understand?
I understand.
Brother.
I want to make more friends
and see the wider world.
When I get to the Capital,
if I have no one to talk to,
I'll write to you,
okay?
Don't.
I don't have time
to read your naggy letter.
Brother.
How about this?
After a few days,
I have a batch of ink
to deliver to the north.
If I have time,
I'll visit you in the Capital.
I don't want you to visit.
If not me, then who?
What's wrong?
Brother,
I think my tooth fell out.
It really did.
According to the ink guild rules,
this tooth should be inspected
by the Grandmaster.
You don't study ink making.
Why show it to him?
Upper or lower tooth?
Upper.
Let me see.
Come with me.
I never cared
about the rules,
but I still made Luo Ink into Tribute Ink.
You should be the same.
Do what you want with all your heart.
Forget the family rules.
One day,
I will make Luo Ink
the best of Hui Ink.
If you go into business when you grow up,
help me
open Luo Ink shops all over the world.
Deal?
Deal.
Then...
let's go.
Let's go!
[Boya Garden]
Young Master, hurry.
Father, Mother,
I've asked around.
The city gate has a butcher shop,
a tofu shop,
a clinic,
and a food stall.
The food stall's owner is Mr. Shui.
He's very nice.
He's an old acquaintance of Grandpa too.
Zhen is back?
Here,
for you.
[Just like pine smoke]
-Jingfu!
-Father!
Father!
Jingfu! Jingfu!
Doctor,
is my son's condition serious?
The patient was already
suffering from tuberculosis
and his body was severely weakened.
Recently,
he must have
suffered some hardships.
Coupled with excessive worry,
it accelerated his illness.
Doctor, just tell us,
how do we treat it?
My medical skills are lacking.
I really can't do anything.
If you could invite
the miracle doctor, Old Master Xue,
there might still be hope.
But Old Master Xue is renowned.
I'm afraid
only wealthy families can invite him.
I'll take my leave.
Mother, I'll go to Seventh Grandmother.
She won't just sit by and watch.
I'll go with Zhen.
Help!
Open the door! Is anyone there?
Is anyone there? Please save my father!
Young Master Zhengliang,
Miss Zhen, why are you here?
Mr. Zhou,
my father is seriously ill.
We need Seventh Grandmother
to invite Old Master Xue.
Please let us see Seventh Grandmother.
Mr. Zhou, I beg you.
Please save my father.
All right.
I'll go in and announce you.
Wait a moment.
Halt.
You can't go.
Please come out!
Third Master Chen
has already invited Doctor Xue over.
He should be fine now.
That Tian Jiangyue.
It's a matter of life and death.
How dare she do such a thing?
Doctor Xue,
how is he?
Seventh Old Madam, First Young Mistress,
I was a step too late.
If strong medicine
had been administered earlier,
perhaps he could have pulled through.
In the end...
it's too late.
Jingfu?
My son,
I don't blame you.
Jingfu.
Didn't you say you'd take us
back to Yi County?
You said that was where I grew up.
You promised us.
Father.
Jingfu,
if you leave,
who will take care of Zhen,
Zhengliang, and me?
Jingfu!
Father,
didn't Doctor Xue come?
He can definitely cure you.
Father!
Jingfu!
[Li Jingfu's Tomb]
Mother,
just because our names
were removed from the family register,
does that mean
we're no longer part of the Li family?
Even if we aren't family,
as one human to another,
how could they just watch him die?
Zhen.
Everyone is different.
But we can't control others.
We must conduct ourselves
so we can answer to heaven and earth,
and to our own consciences.
From today on,
forget about that home.
This is our home now.
Do you understand?
Yes.
Alright.
Don't cry.
Stop crying.
Tomorrow,
I'll set up a silkworm bed here.
Let's raise silkworms.
When the silkworms grow up
and spin their cocoons,
I can make a new outfit for you
and a new pair of shoes for your brother.
But you have to help me
pick mulberry leaves.
Okay?
Okay.
We'll also put a bamboo bed
outside the house.
We can watch the moon in autumn,
the snow in the winter,
and enjoy the cool air in the summer.
We can even watch fireflies.
Look.
There's an empty plot there.
I plan on growing some vegetables
and raising some chickens,
ducks, and geese.
I'll also plant some balsam flowers
outside the courtyard wall
to paint your nails.
Mother.
I want to eat grapes.
Sure.
Then...
Outside,
we'll set up a trellis
and grow grapes for you.
Mother,
will everything you just said
really come true?
Of course.
It definitely will.
I promise you.
Come on.
[Ten years later]
Zhen,
are you up yet?
I've been up for a while!
Zhen,
there are two boiled eggs on the table.
Take them with you to eat on the road.
Grandpa!
Going to work?
Here, leave it to me.
You go to work. Be a good girl.
Give it to me.
Hurry up.
Zhen, let me do it.
Go to work.
Grandpa, let me do it.
Why haven't you left for work yet?
I still have some time.
Go to work.
Got it.
Grandpa, Mother, I'm leaving.
Eat lunch without me.
I have to work at the silk shop
this afternoon.
Be careful on the road.
Say hello to Mr. Shui for me.
Mr. Wu!
Going out, Zhen?
Going to work.
Catch me!
Slow down.
Zhen is here?
Morning!
Morning.
Mr. Shui.
Morning!
Morning.
Zhen.
Here, collect the tea leaves.
Okay!
Did you see it today?
The Ten-li Bridal Procession
was spectacular.
I think in Huizhou, it's called...
Full Phoenix Procession.
Is that it?
Yes, exactly.
That's right!
Miss,
what kind of family
can use this Full Phoenix Procession?
Are there any rules?
When a Huizhou woman marries,
they dig a well at the groom's house.
Those with wealth and means
provide a 480-piece
Full Phoenix Procession.
It's to give their daughter support
when living in her husband's home.
It means all her future expenses
are covered by her maiden family,
so she won't have to be subservient
or live at anyone's mercy.
Server, a pot of tea.
Coming!
Mr. Shui,
I'll take care of him.
Okay.
Sir, what would you like to drink?
What do you recommend?
Why don't you try
our new Xianchun tea?
Sure, I'll have a pot of Xianchun.
Sir,
you're from Yangzhou, aren't you?
How did you know I'm from Yangzhou?
Sesame candy is a Yangzhou specialty.
Besides, people from Yangzhou
love having "meat tea",
pairing tea with savory snacks.
I just put two and two together.
Young lady,
you really are knowledgeable.
Here is your Xianchun tea.
Let it steep for a while before drinking.
Okay.
Here, let me help you.
No, no, no need.
I've got it.
Just a quick helping hand.
Thank you.
Sir,
you're in the fur business, aren't you?
Exactly.
These are all goods I imported
from Qingyang.
Speaking of the fur business,
the biggest boss in Huizhou is Jiao Ke.
Have you visited him before?
You mean Boss Jiao?
I know of him,
but he only deals in bulk.
Small merchants like me
are nothing to him.
Even if I went there,
I wouldn't be able to get any goods.
I actually have a way
that might allow you
to get goods from Boss Jiao.
Really?
But some things
are hard to say out loud.
I understand, I understand.
Miss,
give me a pot of your most expensive tea,
the Shexian Lianxin Tea.
Coming right up.
Mr. Shui,
Get a pot of Shexian Lianxin Tea!
Coming.
This Boss Jiao
has a mistress
in the west of the city,
This woman
often brings back some furs to sell.
Why don't you
go check her place out?
Thank you, Miss.
You're welcome.
Wait a moment.
Okay.
Take it.
Mr. Shui,
why are you giving me so much?
If it weren't for you,
my Shexian Lianxin Tea
would mold before it could sell.
Then,
I'll accept it.
Take it, take it.
Child,
let me say a bit more.
You're marrying into
the newly noble Tian family.
Your dowry cannot be shabby.
Has your family prepared
a Full Phoenix Procession for you?
Mr. Shui,
I don't care about those things.
Marriage is about
marrying a person, not things.
Besides,
I have Benchang,
Mom, Grandpa, and my brother.
They are my true backing.
Well said.
Our Zhen
has plenty of confidence.
You're my backing too!
Mother,
here.
Why is there more than usual today?
This morning,
[The eldest son of the Li Family's
Eighth Branch, Li Zhengliang]
the prefect held a birthday banquet
and many guests got drunk.
I made over a dozen trips
with the sedan chair.
I split the earnings with Zhou.
After deducting the sedan rental fee,
this is what is left.
That is wonderful.
The Captain's daughter-in-law
is giving birth soon.
I spoke with the steward.
to help in the kitchen
during the full month banquet.
and earn some extra money.
Even if we cannot afford
half a Phoenix Procession,
it will still help with expenses later.
We will not let Zhen suffer.
Right.
Grandpa.
Father.
What... what is this?
Zhen is getting married.
I have to support her too.
Grandpa,
where did you get so much money?
Chen San is opening a new shop.
I forced him to only use
my tables and chairs.
He paid me in advance.
I have to rush these next few days
to get it done for him.
Mother, I will go help.
Take care of Grandpa.
Mr. Shui,
is Zhen here?
Yes.
[Daughter of the Tian family,
Tian Ronghua]
Sister-in-law.
Who told you to call me that?
Stop it.
My good sister-in-law,
what magic spell
did you cast on my brother?
After he returned from
delivering bamboo shoots to you that day,
he kept pestering Mother,
telling her
to set the wedding date immediately.
As for him,
he just buried himself
in the ink workshop.
He eats and sleeps there,
not coming out day or night.
So,
you know everything?
I know what I need to know.
The shops don't look busy right now.
Let's go to the jewelry shop
and pick out some headpieces and hairpins
for you to wear at the wedding.
I am not going.
First, over the years,
I have saved up quite a few hairpins.
They are enough.
Second,
I have a lot of expenses right now.
I cannot spend money recklessly.
What do you need so much money for?
Let me list them for you.
Our roof is leaking,
so I have to fix it.
Buying medicine
for Grandpa costs money too.
As for my brother,
it looks like he has found someone.
I have to save some for him too.
We cannot let others
look down on him, right?
And the family needs
money to buy silkworms
and plant mulberry trees
to make good fabric for my mother.
She would never bear to
buy it for herself.
And...
Zhen,
you are amazing.
It's nothing.
You know how hard
it's been for our family these years.
Not just me,
but Grandpa, Mother, and my brother
are all like this.
We plan carefully
and look out for each other.
That's how we get by.
No wonder my brother
is determined to marry you.
A housekeeper wife as capable as you
can't be found anywhere else in Huizhou.
No way.
I have to be on my best behavior too.
Otherwise, after you marry in,
you'll probably
start bossing me around too.
Hua,
you're starting up again, aren't you?
I'm gonna get you!
You run pretty fast.
You greedy girl.
Grandpa and your brother aren't back yet.
Don't steal food.
I only had one piece.
Zhen,
that Benchang
is always bringing things over.
And now,
why are you even letting him
chop the wood?
I didn't force him.
He insisted.
He said my brother is too busy working,
so he insisted on coming with me.
This is for you.
Zhen,
[The eldest son of the Tian Family,
Tian Benchang]
is this...
When children of the Ink Guild marry,
exchanging the birthday inkstick
is seen as a vow.
Since we are engaged,
my birthday inkstick
naturally belongs to you.
Zhen,
from now on,
I will carry it with me every day
and cherish it.
I almost forgot to tell you something.
This is the ink order
I negotiated with Registrar Zhang today.
Once this order is filled,
my family's ink workshop will be on track,
and I can give you a better life.
Such a large order...
Given the current scale of your workshop,
isn't it a bit too rushed?
The new lampblack shed
is already being built.
The schedule is tight,
but for you
and our future,
I have to take the chance.
But don't worry.
It's a bit risky,
but I will make sure this order
is delivered smoothly,
and then I'll give you a grand wedding.
I'll be waiting.
I'm off then.
Take care on the way.
Master Liu,
how is the quality
of this batch of lampblack?
[Lampblack: a charcoal ash used for making ink.
It's from ash collected from burning material.]
Uneven texture,
inconsistent color.
All low grade.
How is that possible?
The lampblack collection process
is simple.
The workers are all experienced masters.
I screened the raw materials myself
and I supervised the work.
There shouldn't be any problems.
In your opinion,
where does the problem lie?
Did you build this new shed
strictly according to the specifications?
It was built to scale
based on the dimensions
of the Luo Ink sheds.
That's strange.
If it's an exact replica
of the Luo family's shed,
the product shouldn't
all be of low grade.
Master Liu,
why don't we produce
another batch and see?
The workshop has an order
waiting to be fulfilled.
What did you agree to?
When is the delivery date
for Registrar Zhang's order?
Five hundred sticks
of medium-quality ink a month later.
A month?
Mr. Tian,
at this rate,
I'm afraid you won't make it.
Let me ask you,
how much is the penalty
for a late delivery?
Ten times.
Ten times?
Even mortgaging our entire ink workshop
wouldn't be enough to cover that.
We only have one option left.
We must beg Young Master Wensong.
We're learning the Luo Ink method,
after all.
Besides,
Master Luo
wrote from the capital recently.
He agreed to
Young Master Luo and Ronghua's marriage.
Ronghua's marriage?
Don't worry about that.
As long as we tell him the truth,
he might be willing to help.
Where did it go wrong?
[Jingxin Hall]
Aunt, Wensong is here to see you.
What do you want?
Aunt,
I'm using the newly acquired
thousand-year pine soot
to develop new tribute ink,
but the mixing keeps failing,
so I came to ask for your advice.
I taught you everything
when you were young.
I have nothing left to teach.
This tribute ink matter
concerns the future of the Luo family.
Could you...
Say no more.
[Luo Hanqiong's sister
Luo Mengzhen]
I can't help you.
Aunt,
I'm in charge of the Luo family now.
If I can't develop the tribute ink,
how will the Luo family stand
in the Huizhou ink industry?
I beg you.
Please help me.
Since the day I was widowed
before marriage,
the Luo family and I
have had nothing to do with each other.
Leave.
I won't get up unless you help me.
If you don't leave,
don't ever
come back again.
Young Master.
The Tians are here again.
What for?
He says there's a problem
with the shed dimensions you taught him.
A problem with what I taught him?
That's what he said.
Useless.
I won't see them.
Okay,
I'll tell them to get lost.
Ping'an!
What is it, Young Master?
Is the marriage between Tian Benchang
and the girl from the Li family's
Eighth Branch settled?
Yes.
Call them in.
Yes, sir.
Young Master,
what is the meaning of this?
You produced such inferior lampblack,
yet you dare claim
it was made according to
the specifications of my Luo Ink sheds?
Young Master,
please don't be angry.
We were just afraid of
tarnishing the Luo Ink's reputation,
so we came to ask for your guidance.
My father values old ties.
He removed
the Tian family's slave status
and let you use
the Luo family's techniques
to do some small business.
But look at you.
Instead of putting any effort
into figuring out how to make good ink,
you cut corners
and use Luo family products
to swindle others.
How dare you ask me for guidance?
Young Master,
look,
we're about to become one family.
How are we family?
Didn't Master Luo
send a letter from the capital?
He tacitly approved
your marriage to Hua.
Hua is indeed
a gentle child.
Rest assured,
she will take good care of you
after the marriage
and share your burdens.
You've really calculated this well.
You send your son to marry
an outcast of the Li family,
and then shove your daughter onto me.
You two
keep talking about
devotion to ink,
but what are you actually doing?
As long as you can protect
the Tian family's interests,
you'll do anything.
Hey—
Father!
Young Master,
don't be angry.
Please show some mercy
and help us.
Fine.
Tian Benchang.
Go to the Li family
and borrow their ink formula
for me to take a look.
That's impossible!
That is the Li family's secret formula.
How could they lend it to outsiders?
Didn't your father just say
that once you marry the Li girl,
you'll be one family?
How are you outsiders then?
I, Luo Wensong, always keep my word,
and I keep kindness and grudges distinct.
As long as you can bring me that formula,
I will not only help you build the shed,
but I will also
take your family's ink making
to the next level.
I'll let you see
what true ink making is.
But if you can't borrow it,
Tian Huai'an,
even if you marry your daughter over,
I can still divorce her.
Luo Wensong,
you've gone too far!
Chang.
You—
Father!
Get out.
It's already—
You... Never mind.
Young Master,
I understand
what you mean.
Leave this matter
to me.
Father,
why did you agree to him?
I can't possibly bring this up
with Li Zhen.
Useless fool.
Can't you tell?
This concerns the very survival
of our ink workshop.
Now, even your sister's marriage
is involved in this.
And you're too embarrassed to speak up?
Do you want to ruin both things?
I never thought
Ronghua's marriage to him was appropriate.
Luo Wensong's two previous wives
both died young.
People say he's cursed to be a widower.
Besides, he has a terrible temper.
If Ronghua marries him,
she will never have a good life.
What do you know?
The Luo family is prestigious and wealthy.
Hua will be
marrying up.
We should be thanking our lucky stars
and you're unhappy about it?
If you continue to be this muddled,
I will go to the Li family right now
and call off your marriage
to Zhen.
Listen to me.
I'll tell you
my plan.
All these years,
I had you get close
to the Li family's Eighth Branch
wasn't just to
offer help in their hour of need
when they were at their lowest.
Since you were young,
I saw that you were kind, righteous,
and capable of achieving great things.
That's why I faciliated
your marriage with Zhen.
I want more than you do,
and I think further ahead than you.
There are so many ink experts in Huizhou,
all with deep pockets
and generations of heritage.
But our Tian family
entered the ink industry empty-handed.
Every step we take
must be carved out for ourselves.
You don't understand
the dangers at every turn,
but I must consider
the future of our family.
That's why I'm having you marry Li Zhen,
and that's why I'm having
Hua marry Master Luo.
It's all part of the same plan.
Think about it carefully.
Don't come back until you figure it out.